<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<LanguageData>  

  <RV2R_Settings_Tab>Rut's Stuff</RV2R_Settings_Tab> 
  
  <RV2R_Encumberance_Section>Encumbrance</RV2R_Encumberance_Section>
	
  <RV2R_Settings_SizedEncumberance>Size-based encumbrance scaling</RV2R_Settings_SizedEncumberance>  
  <RV2R_Settings_SizedEncumberance_Tip>Enable to scale encumberance by total weight of all prey. Disable to scale encumberance by count of prey, Can cause problems for smaller preds.</RV2R_Settings_SizedEncumberance_Tip>  
  <RV2R_Settings_EncumberanceModifier>Encumbrance multiplier</RV2R_Settings_EncumberanceModifier>  
  <RV2R_Settings_EncumberanceModifier_Tip>How heavy prey are. Setting too high can easily incapacitate preds. Prey held in extremiedies or absorbed in some way are easier to hold.</RV2R_Settings_EncumberanceModifier_Tip>  

  <RV2R_Tick_Section>Endo Stuff</RV2R_Tick_Section>

  <RV2R_Settings_EndoSickness>Endo sickness strength</RV2R_Settings_EndoSickness>  
  <RV2R_Settings_EndoSickness_Tip>How quickly (if at all) a pawn should get "endo sick" while safely inside of a pred. At default, it's 1% severity per "vore tick". It's not dangerous, and even puts them in a good mood, at the cost of being loopy and disorientated for about a day or two.\n\nIndirectly nerfs endo storage as a way to keep medics and such safe and makes struggling harder, among other things.</RV2R_Settings_EndoSickness_Tip>  
  <RV2R_Settings_EndoSicknessPacification>Endo pacification</RV2R_Settings_EndoSicknessPacification>  
  <RV2R_Settings_EndoSicknessPacification_Tip>Prey that are too endo sick can no longer struggle.</RV2R_Settings_EndoSicknessPacification_Tip>  
  <RV2R_Settings_AgeRegression>Age regression strength</RV2R_Settings_AgeRegression>
  <RV2R_Settings_AgeRegression_Tip>How quickly, in days spent to days gained, prey regress in age while unbirthed. They'll never regress to below biological adulthood, which varies by race. Set to 0 to disable, and to 1 to prevent but not reverse aging.\n\n(Remember that Rimworld has 60 days in a year.)</RV2R_Settings_AgeRegression_Tip>
  <RV2R_Settings_AgeRegressionCure>Chronic regression</RV2R_Settings_AgeRegressionCure>
  <RV2R_Settings_AgeRegressionCure_Tip>Age-regressed prey have a small chance to be cured of chronic illnesses while unbirthed. Odds increase the younger they get.</RV2R_Settings_AgeRegressionCure_Tip>

  <RV2R_Capture_Section>Capturing</RV2R_Capture_Section>
	
  <RV2R_Settings_EndoCapture>Endo capture</RV2R_Settings_EndoCapture>  
  <RV2R_Settings_EndoCapture_Tip>Enabled, hostiles are captured and imprisoned if endo-vored by a colonist or colony animal while downed. Works great with heal-voring incapacitated raiders, and enabling means predatory trained animals have a way to help with recruitment.\n\n(Animals trained in predation will heal-vore hostiles if they can't fatal vore them.)</RV2R_Settings_EndoCapture_Tip>
  <RV2R_Settings_EndoCapture_Insectoids>Capture insectoids</RV2R_Settings_EndoCapture_Insectoids>  
  <RV2R_Settings_EndoCapture_Insectoids_Tip>Members of the Sorne Geneline are pacified if endo-captured, ready to be tamed when released. Not at all balanced.</RV2R_Settings_EndoCapture_Insectoids_Tip>
  <RV2R_Settings_EndoCapture_Scaria>Scaria cure</RV2R_Settings_EndoCapture_Scaria>  
  <RV2R_Settings_EndoCapture_Scaria_Tip>Healing vore can cure scaria, allowing endo-capture to be used on rabid animals. They'll only capture or endo-rescue animals you've set to tame.</RV2R_Settings_EndoCapture_Scaria_Tip>
 
  <RV2R_AnimalNom_Section>Animal Vore</RV2R_AnimalNom_Section>
	
  <RV2R_Settings_AnimalRandomNomChance>Playful predation average hours</RV2R_Settings_AnimalRandomNomChance>
  <RV2R_Settings_AnimalRandomNomChance_Tip>How often, in hours on average, an animal trained to be playfully predatory will endo vore others. They're request vore to colonists, but they'll just nom anything else.</RV2R_Settings_AnimalRandomNomChance_Tip>
  <RV2R_Settings_AnimalRandomNomChanceModifier>Playful predation modifier</RV2R_Settings_AnimalRandomNomChanceModifier>
  <RV2R_Settings_AnimalRandomNomChanceModifier_Tip>The percentage of average hours to add for each prey a playful predator has. At default, 1 prey increases the average hours from 24 to 30, and two increases it to 36.</RV2R_Settings_AnimalRandomNomChanceModifier_Tip>
  <RV2R_Settings_AnimalRandomNomFatal>Not-so-playful predation</RV2R_Settings_AnimalRandomNomFatal>
  <RV2R_Settings_AnimalRandomNomFatal_Tip>...You, uh, might want to leave this off.</RV2R_Settings_AnimalRandomNomFatal_Tip>
  
  <RV2R_Bonds_Section>Bonds</RV2R_Bonds_Section>
	
  <RV2R_Settings_EndoBondChance>Endo bond chance</RV2R_Settings_EndoBondChance>
  <RV2R_Settings_EndoBondChance_Tip>When an animal and a humanoid are engaged in endo vore, they have a chance to form a bond every vore tick. Wild animals can end up bonded too, so keep that in mind when you take that wolf home with you.\n\nYou really should keep this low.</RV2R_Settings_EndoBondChance_Tip>
  <RV2R_Settings_EndoBondPredOnly>Predator bonding</RV2R_Settings_EndoBondPredOnly>
  <RV2R_Settings_EndoBondPredOnly_Tip>Normaly, endo bonds happen only when the pred is humanoid. Enabling means humanoid pawns can bond while endo prey for an animal.\n\nYou might wanna leave this off.</RV2R_Settings_EndoBondPredOnly_Tip>  
  <RV2R_Settings_EndoBondUnwilling>Dom-bonding</RV2R_Settings_EndoBondUnwilling>
  <RV2R_Settings_EndoBondUnwilling_Tip>Normaly, endo bonds happen only when the prey is willing. But who's to say that fox isn't the submissive type?</RV2R_Settings_EndoBondUnwilling_Tip>
  <RV2R_Settings_VornyBonds>Voraphile bonds</RV2R_Settings_VornyBonds>
  <RV2R_Settings_VornyBonds_Tip>Bonded animals are more likely to pick their bond as an play-vore target, and bonds always agree to vore proposals.</RV2R_Settings_VornyBonds_Tip>
  
  <RV2R_Cheats_Section>Cheaty stuff</RV2R_Cheats_Section>
  
  <RV2R_Cheats_NoBleedOut>No bleed out</RV2R_Cheats_NoBleedOut>
  <RV2R_Cheats_NoBleedOut_Tip>Caps a prey's Blood loss hediff to 90%. Dramaticaly lowers fatalies when using healing vore.</RV2R_Cheats_NoBleedOut_Tip>
  <RV2R_Cheats_StopBleeding>Staunch bleeding</RV2R_Cheats_StopBleeding>
  <RV2R_Cheats_StopBleeding_Tip>Prey have their bleeding gradualy lower while vored. Does not tend injuries, just reduces bleeding.</RV2R_Cheats_StopBleeding_Tip>
  <RV2R_Cheats_NoExtremeTemp>No extreme temps</RV2R_Cheats_NoExtremeTemp>
  <RV2R_Cheats_NoExtremeTemp_Tip>Caps a prey's hypothermia and heat stroke hediffs to 30%.</RV2R_Cheats_NoExtremeTemp_Tip>
  <RV2R_Cheats_HyperHealing>Curaga Vore</RV2R_Cheats_HyperHealing>
  <RV2R_Cheats_HyperHealing_Tip>Healing preds start casting curaga instead of cure, dramaticaly improving the best vore goal. Having a skilled doctor tend injuries and then heal-vore is still more effective.</RV2R_Cheats_HyperHealing_Tip>

  <RV2R_FuckUnity>Remember to add\n\n0.0.0.0 *unity.com\n0.0.0.0 *.unity.com\n0.0.0.0 *unity3d.com\n0.0.0.0 *.unity3d.com\n\n to your hosts file. You'll gain a sense of pride and accomplishment, no surprise mechanics needed.\n\n\nRimWorld was created with Unity, which has just decided to fuck over every single developer who has ever used their platform. Show some love to Ludeon Studios and other once-Unity devs.\n\n\nFuck Unity, and fuck John Riccitiello.</RV2R_FuckUnity>

</LanguageData>
