<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<LanguageData>  

  <RV2R_Pet>After spending substanial time stored within {1}, {0} has become {1}'s pet.</RV2R_Pet>
  <RV2R_PetJoined>{0}, having become {1}'s pet, has decided to join your colony.</RV2R_PetJoined>
  <RV2R_RecruitAttempsWillBegin>Once they are released from {0}'s body, recruitment attempts will begin.</RV2R_RecruitAttempsWillBegin>
  
  <RV2R_DesginateDevour>Devour</RV2R_DesginateDevour>
  <RV2R_DesginateDevourDesc>Mark downed hostiles or animals to be devoured by your animals trained in Predation.</RV2R_DesginateDevourDesc>
  <RV2R_DesginateDevourErr>Must designate downed hostiles or animals.</RV2R_DesginateDevourErr>
  <RV2R_DesginateDevourErrHuman>Targets cannot be fatal-vored, and endo-capture is disabled in settings.</RV2R_DesginateDevourErrHuman>
  <RV2R_DesginateDevourErrScaria>Targets cannot be fatal-vored, and scaria-infected creatures cannot be endo-captured - Disabled in settings.</RV2R_DesginateDevourErrScaria>
  <RV2R_DesginateDevourErrInsect>Targets cannot be fatal-vored, and insectoids cannot be endo-captured - Disabled in settings.</RV2R_DesginateDevourErrInsect>
  
  <RV2R_Settings_Tab>Rut's Stuff</RV2R_Settings_Tab> 
  
  <RV2R_Encumberance_Section>Encumbrance</RV2R_Encumberance_Section>
	
  <RV2R_Settings_SizedEncumberance>Size-based encumbrance scaling</RV2R_Settings_SizedEncumberance>  
  <RV2R_Settings_SizedEncumberance_Tip>Enable to scale encumberance by total weight of all prey. Disable to scale encumberance by count of prey, Can cause problems for smaller preds.</RV2R_Settings_SizedEncumberance_Tip>  
  <RV2R_Settings_EncumberanceModifier>Encumbrance multiplier</RV2R_Settings_EncumberanceModifier>  
  <RV2R_Settings_EncumberanceModifier_Tip>How heavy prey are. Setting too high can easily incapacitate preds.</RV2R_Settings_EncumberanceModifier_Tip>   
  <RV2R_Settings_EncumberanceVisible>Visible "Weighed down" hediff</RV2R_Settings_EncumberanceVisible>  
  <RV2R_Settings_EncumberanceVisible_Tip>Makes the "weighed down" hediff used for encumbrance visible. This dosn't change it's functonality, it just makes it visible to the player.</RV2R_Settings_EncumberanceVisible_Tip> 
  <RV2R_Settings_EncumberanceTurnOff>Due to how the encumbrance scaling works, disabling size-based encumbrance scaling will not revert to RimVore-2's methods for encumbrance, instead using a method that aproximates it.\n\nIf you need to revert, set encumbrance multiplier to 0% and remove Patches/Patch_Hediffs_Vore_CapmodRemoval.xml from this submod's Common folder.</RV2R_Settings_EncumberanceTurnOff>  

  <RV2R_Tick_Section>Endo Stuff</RV2R_Tick_Section>

  <RV2R_Settings_EndoSickness>Endo sickness strength</RV2R_Settings_EndoSickness>  
  <RV2R_Settings_EndoSickness_Tip>How quickly (if at all) a pawn should get "endo sick" while safely inside of a pred. At default, it's 1% severity per "vore tick". It's not dangerous, and even puts them in a good mood, at the cost of being loopy and disorientated for about a day or two.\n\nIndirectly nerfs endo storage as a way to keep medics and such safe, lowers food need of belly pets and makes struggling harder, among other things.</RV2R_Settings_EndoSickness_Tip>  
  <RV2R_Settings_EndoSicknessPacification>Endo pacification</RV2R_Settings_EndoSicknessPacification>  
  <RV2R_Settings_EndoSicknessPacification_Tip>Prey that are too endo sick can no longer struggle, and will be captured if hostile.</RV2R_Settings_EndoSicknessPacification_Tip>  
  <RV2R_Settings_AgeRegression>Age regression strength</RV2R_Settings_AgeRegression>
  <RV2R_Settings_AgeRegression_Tip>How quickly, in days spent to days gained, prey regress in age while unbirthed. They'll never regress to below biological adulthood, which varies by race. Set to 0 to disable, and to 1 to prevent but not reverse aging.\n\n(Remember that Rimworld has 60 days in a year.)</RV2R_Settings_AgeRegression_Tip>
  <RV2R_Settings_AgeRegressionCure>Chronic regression</RV2R_Settings_AgeRegressionCure>
  <RV2R_Settings_AgeRegressionCure_Tip>Age-regressed prey have a small chance to be cured of chronic illnesses while unbirthed. Odds increase the younger they get.</RV2R_Settings_AgeRegressionCure_Tip>
  <RV2R_Settings_Pets>Endo pets</RV2R_Settings_Pets>
  <RV2R_Settings_Pets_Tip>Predators and prey who willingly spend this many days straight in a vore stage gain a special relationship, providing a permanate opinion boost. Can be abused, but pets and their preds will get upset if something happens to the other.</RV2R_Settings_Pets_Tip>
  <RV2R_Settings_PetsColonyOnly>Only colonists become pets</RV2R_Settings_PetsColonyOnly>
  <RV2R_Settings_PetsColonyOnly_Tip>Only allow members of your colony to become endo-bonded.</RV2R_Settings_PetsColonyOnly_Tip>
  <RV2R_Settings_PetRecruitment>Pets join</RV2R_Settings_PetRecruitment>
  <RV2R_Settings_PetRecruitment_Tip>Prey will join your faction if they become a pet of one of your pawns. Can very easily be abused.</RV2R_Settings_PetRecruitment_Tip>
  <RV2R_Settings_EndoThoughts>Relationship Thoughts</RV2R_Settings_EndoThoughts>
  <RV2R_Settings_EndoThoughts_Tip>Lets preds and prey gain positive thoughts if they're in a relationship or bonded, based on their opinion of each other.n\n\At most, it's +5 mood for lovers, +5 mood for holding 2 bonded animals, and +5 mood for belly pets.</RV2R_Settings_EndoThoughts_Tip>

  <RV2R_Capture_Section>Capturing</RV2R_Capture_Section>
	
  <RV2R_Settings_EndoCapture>Endo capture</RV2R_Settings_EndoCapture>  
  <RV2R_Settings_EndoCapture_Tip>Enabled, hostiles are captured and imprisoned if endo-vored by a colonist or colony animal while downed. Works great with heal-voring incapacitated raiders, and enabling means predatory trained animals have a way to help with recruitment.\n\n(Animals trained in predation will heal-vore hostiles if they can't fatal vore them.)</RV2R_Settings_EndoCapture_Tip>
  <RV2R_Settings_EndoCapture_Insectoids>Capture insectoids</RV2R_Settings_EndoCapture_Insectoids>  
  <RV2R_Settings_EndoCapture_Insectoids_Tip>Members of the Sorne Geneline are pacified if endo-captured, ready to be tamed when released.</RV2R_Settings_EndoCapture_Insectoids_Tip>  
  <RV2R_Settings_EndoCapture_Scaria>Scaria cure</RV2R_Settings_EndoCapture_Scaria>  
  <RV2R_Settings_EndoCapture_Scaria_Tip>Healing vore can cure scaria, allowing endo-capture to be used on rabid animals.</RV2R_Settings_EndoCapture_Scaria_Tip>
  <RV2R_Settings_EndoCapture_Recruitment>Endo recruitment</RV2R_Settings_EndoCapture_Recruitment>  
  <RV2R_Settings_EndoCapture_Recruitment_Tip>Prisoners set to "Reduce Resistance" or "Recruit" will have their resistance slowly lower while willingly endo-vored. Having a warden chat them up is still faster, and this won't sway the unwavering.</RV2R_Settings_EndoCapture_Recruitment_Tip>
  
  <RV2R_Settings_EndoCaptureDevourFriendlies>Devour-designate friendlies</RV2R_Settings_EndoCaptureDevourFriendlies> 
  <RV2R_Settings_EndoCaptureDevourFriendlies_Tip>Allows you to designate downed friendlies as devour targets. Could be a bad idea, or used with heal-vore and gizmo-designations as an alternate rescue method.</RV2R_Settings_EndoCaptureDevourFriendlies_Tip>   
  <RV2R_Settings_EndoCaptureDevourColonists>Devour-designate colonists</RV2R_Settings_EndoCaptureDevourColonists> 
  <RV2R_Settings_EndoCaptureDevourColonists_Tip>Allows you to designate downed colonists as devour targets. Could be a bad idea, or used with heal-vore and gizmo-designations as an alternate rescue method.</RV2R_Settings_EndoCaptureDevourColonists_Tip> 
  <RV2R_Settings_EndoCaptureDevourColonistsFull>Devour-designate non-downed colonists</RV2R_Settings_EndoCaptureDevourColonistsFull> 
  <RV2R_Settings_EndoCaptureDevourColonistsFull_Tip>Don't ask "Why?" - instead, ask "Yes."\n\n(Animals will use random endo goals if they're not hurt and can't be fatal vored.)</RV2R_Settings_EndoCaptureDevourColonistsFull_Tip> 
  
  <RV2R_Lovin_Section>Lovin'</RV2R_Lovin_Section>
  
  <RV2R_Settings_PreyLovin>Voraphile 3-ways</RV2R_Settings_PreyLovin>
  <RV2R_Settings_PreyLovin_Tip>Lets prey have some fun if their predators engage in lovin'. How much (if at all) a prey enjoys it is based on their Preyish Libido quirks.</RV2R_Settings_PreyLovin_Tip>
  <RV2R_Settings_GutLovin>Gut lovin' chance</RV2R_Settings_GutLovin>
  <RV2R_Settings_GutLovin_Tip>How likely a romanticaly involved pred/prey pair will engage in some endophilic lovin'. It works like regular lovin', respects lovin's cooldown, and both need to consent for it to happen. Odds are affected by their Predatory and Preyish Libido quirks.</RV2R_Settings_GutLovin_Tip>
  <RV2R_Settings_GutLovinSapient>Sapient creatures allowed</RV2R_Settings_GutLovinSapient>
  <RV2R_Settings_GutLovinSapient_Tip>Allows anything that can give informed consent to both get and give some gut lovin'. Works with Sentiant Animals, Pawnmorphers' former humans and Kyulen, among others.</RV2R_Settings_GutLovinSapient_Tip>
  <RV2R_Settings_GutLovinONS>One-nom-stands</RV2R_Settings_GutLovinONS>
  <RV2R_Settings_GutLovinONS_Tip>Sufficiantly "vorny" pairs won't care if they're not romanticaly involved. Those with partners will refrain if their partner isn't involved.</RV2R_Settings_GutLovinONS_Tip>   
  <RV2R_Settings_GutLovinFlings>Vorny flings</RV2R_Settings_GutLovinFlings>
  <RV2R_Settings_GutLovinFlings_Tip>Allows predators with a lover to gut-love if they're not involved. Has no penalties or negitive effects, but can make for awkward looking situations.</RV2R_Settings_GutLovinFlings_Tip>  
  <RV2R_Settings_GutLovinNonCon>Allow non-con</RV2R_Settings_GutLovinNonCon>
  <RV2R_Settings_GutLovinNonCon_Tip>Allows for psycopaths or low opinion preds to gut-love regardless of what their prey think. Will absolutly destroy relationships, and Kind pawns just won't.</RV2R_Settings_GutLovinNonCon_Tip>
	
  <RV2R_Fodder_Section>Living meals</RV2R_Fodder_Section>
  
  <RV2R_Settings_Fodder_Chance>Fodder chance</RV2R_Settings_Fodder_Chance>
  <RV2R_Settings_Fodder_Chance_Tip>How likely colonists will vore a prisoner marked as fodder instead of getting a regular meal. They won't if they're too far away, or if they don't like any goals avialable to them.\n\nIf they can't reach -any- food, this check will always succeed.\n\nThis can dramaticaly increase the amount of auto-vore happening, for better or for worse.</RV2R_Settings_Fodder_Chance_Tip>
  <RV2R_Settings_Fodder_AllowNamed>Named animals can fodder</RV2R_Settings_Fodder_AllowNamed>
  <RV2R_Settings_Fodder_AllowNamed_Tip>Allows named colony animals to fodder prisoners. Any animal can be named in their Training tab.</RV2R_Settings_Fodder_AllowNamed_Tip>
  <RV2R_Settings_Fodder_AllowPredators>Colony predators can fodder</RV2R_Settings_Fodder_AllowPredators>
  <RV2R_Settings_Fodder_AllowPredators_Tip>Allows predatory colony animals to fodder prisoners. Their odds are lower than colonists.</RV2R_Settings_Fodder_AllowPredators_Tip>
  <RV2R_Settings_Fodder_AllowAnimals>Colony animals can fodder</RV2R_Settings_Fodder_AllowAnimals>
  <RV2R_Settings_Fodder_AllowAnimals_Tip>Allows all colony animals to fodder prisoners. Allowing predators must be enabled for this to have an effect. Their odds are lower than predator animals.</RV2R_Settings_Fodder_AllowAnimals_Tip>
  <RV2R_Settings_Fodder_AnimalsFull>Colony animals can fodder non-prisoners</RV2R_Settings_Fodder_AnimalsFull>
  <RV2R_Settings_Fodder_AnimalsFull_Tip>Allows colony animals to follow the fodder rules below. Can cause things to get a little chaotic, particularly in large colonies. Farm animals will never fodder others.</RV2R_Settings_Fodder_AnimalsFull_Tip>
    
  <RV2R_Settings_MiscFodder_Chance>Misc. fodder chance</RV2R_Settings_MiscFodder_Chance>
  <RV2R_Settings_MiscFodder_Chance_Tip>How likely voring a non-prisoner pawn will happen instead of getting a regular meal.\n\nThis can and will dramaticaly increase the amount of auto-vore happening, for better or for worse.</RV2R_Settings_MiscFodder_Chance_Tip>

  <RV2R_Settings_Fodder_Penned>Pen animals are fodder</RV2R_Settings_Fodder_Penned>
  <RV2R_Settings_Fodder_Penned_Tip>If farm animals are valid fodder meals. Fodder prisoners have higher odds to be chosen, any living meal based on friendlies/non-hostiles have a base chance to fail, and 2 males and females of any species will be spared.</RV2R_Settings_Fodder_Penned_Tip>
  <RV2R_Settings_Fodder_Animal>Colony animals are fodder</RV2R_Settings_Fodder_Animal>
  <RV2R_Settings_Fodder_Animal_Tip>If non-predatory or small colony animals are valid fodder meals. Each trainable leared lowers the odds of being chosen, named animals are spared, and 2 males and females of any species will be spared.</RV2R_Settings_Fodder_Animal_Tip>
  <RV2R_Settings_Fodder_Predator>Colony predators are fodder</RV2R_Settings_Fodder_Predator>
  <RV2R_Settings_Fodder_Predator_Tip>If predatory colony animals are valid fodder meals. Each trainable leared lowers the odds of being chosen, named animals are spared, and 2 males and females of any species will be spared.</RV2R_Settings_Fodder_Predator_Tip>
  <RV2R_Settings_Fodder_Guests>Colony guests are fodder</RV2R_Settings_Fodder_Guests>
  <RV2R_Settings_Fodder_Guests_Tip>You really should leave this off.</RV2R_Settings_Fodder_Guests_Tip>
  <RV2R_Settings_Fodder_Colonists>Colonists are fodder</RV2R_Settings_Fodder_Colonists>
  <RV2R_Settings_Fodder_Colonists_Tip>You -REALLY- should leave this off.\n\n(They can use the drain vore-goal, making this a significantly less bad idea, but having fractions of your colony vanish every other day and come back loopy/passing out is more than a little chaotic.)</RV2R_Settings_Fodder_Colonists_Tip>
  
  <RV2R_AnimalNom_Section>Animal Vore</RV2R_AnimalNom_Section>
	
  <RV2R_Settings_AnimalRandomNomChance>Playful predation average hours</RV2R_Settings_AnimalRandomNomChance>
  <RV2R_Settings_AnimalRandomNomChance_Tip>How often, in hours on average, an animal trained to be playfully predatory will endo vore others. They'll only do so when idle, and when not near danger. They're request vore to colonists, but they'll just nom anything else.\n\nPlayful predation can be disabled on an animal by disabling training it in their Training tab.</RV2R_Settings_AnimalRandomNomChance_Tip>
  <RV2R_Settings_AnimalRandomNomChanceModifier>Playful predation modifier</RV2R_Settings_AnimalRandomNomChanceModifier>
  <RV2R_Settings_AnimalRandomNomChanceModifier_Tip>The percentage of average hours to add for each prey a playful predator has. At default settings, 1 prey increases the average hours from 24 to 36, and two increases it to 48.</RV2R_Settings_AnimalRandomNomChanceModifier_Tip>
  <RV2R_Settings_AnimalRandomNomColonistModifier>Playful predation colonist chance</RV2R_Settings_AnimalRandomNomColonistModifier>
  <RV2R_Settings_AnimalRandomNomColonistModifier_Tip>The odds a colonist will be a valid play-pred target. Setting to 0% means only bonded animals can play-pred colonists, and only if Voraphile Bonds is enabled.</RV2R_Settings_AnimalRandomNomColonistModifier_Tip>
  <RV2R_Settings_AnimalRandomNomIndiscriminate>Indescriminate predation</RV2R_Settings_AnimalRandomNomIndiscriminate>
  <RV2R_Settings_AnimalRandomNomIndiscriminate_Tip>Allows playfuly predatory animals to nom anyone, not just colony members. Can cause problems.</RV2R_Settings_AnimalRandomNomIndiscriminate_Tip>
  <RV2R_Settings_AnimalRandomNomFatal>Not-so-playful predation</RV2R_Settings_AnimalRandomNomFatal>
  <RV2R_Settings_AnimalRandomNomFatal_Tip>Playful predation is safe. Not-so-playful predation is, potentialy, unsafe.\n\nYou might want to leave this off.</RV2R_Settings_AnimalRandomNomFatal_Tip>
  
  <RV2R_Bonds_Section>Bonds</RV2R_Bonds_Section>
	
  <RV2R_Settings_EndoBondChance>Endo bond chance</RV2R_Settings_EndoBondChance>
  <RV2R_Settings_EndoBondChance_Tip>When an animal and a humanoid are engaged in endo vore, they have a chance to form a bond every vore tick. Bonds give a mood boost to their bonded masters, and are easier for them to tame and train, though they'll get upset if the other dies.\n\nWild animals can end up bonded too, so keep that in mind when you take that wolf home with you.\n\nYou really should keep this low.</RV2R_Settings_EndoBondChance_Tip>
  <RV2R_Settings_EndoBondPredOnly>Predator bonding</RV2R_Settings_EndoBondPredOnly>
  <RV2R_Settings_EndoBondPredOnly_Tip>Normaly, endo bonds can happen only when the pred is humanoid. Enabling means humanoid pawns can bond while endo prey for an animal. With playful predation, this can lead to most of your animals bonded.\n\nYou might wanna leave this off.</RV2R_Settings_EndoBondPredOnly_Tip>  
  <RV2R_Settings_EndoBondUnwilling>Dom-bonding</RV2R_Settings_EndoBondUnwilling>
  <RV2R_Settings_EndoBondUnwilling_Tip>Normaly, endo bonds can happen only when the prey is willing. But who's to say that wolf isn't the submissive type?</RV2R_Settings_EndoBondUnwilling_Tip>
  <RV2R_Settings_VornyBonds>Voraphile bonds</RV2R_Settings_VornyBonds>
  <RV2R_Settings_VornyBonds_Tip>Bonded animals are more likely to pick their bond as an play-vore target, and bonds always agree to vore proposals.</RV2R_Settings_VornyBonds_Tip>
  
  <RV2R_Cheats_Section>Cheaty stuff</RV2R_Cheats_Section>
  
  <RV2R_Cheats_PreyJoy>Prey recreation</RV2R_Cheats_PreyJoy>
  <RV2R_Cheats_PreyJoy_Tip>Prey that are at least okay about being prey gain passive recreation need while vored. It caps at 33% if forced, and 50% otherwise.</RV2R_Cheats_PreyJoy_Tip>
  <RV2R_Cheats_MetabolismBoost>Metabolic efficency</RV2R_Cheats_MetabolismBoost>
  <RV2R_Cheats_MetabolismBoost_Tip>Predators with hightened metabolic efficency get rebates when their food need is lowered by healing or sharing with prey. Will increase food need loss if metabolism is weakened.\n\nMakes giving your jail-cell/healer preds bionic stomachs/livers a good idea.</RV2R_Cheats_MetabolismBoost_Tip>
  <RV2R_Cheats_NoBleedOut>No bleed out</RV2R_Cheats_NoBleedOut>
  <RV2R_Cheats_NoBleedOut_Tip>Caps a prey's Blood loss hediff to 90%. Dramaticaly lowers fatalty rates when using healing vore. Can still be indirectly lethal.</RV2R_Cheats_NoBleedOut_Tip>
  <RV2R_Cheats_StopBleeding>Staunch bleeding</RV2R_Cheats_StopBleeding>
  <RV2R_Cheats_StopBleeding_Tip>Prey have their bleeding gradualy lower while vored. Does not tend injuries, just reduces bleeding. Dramaticaly reduces fatality rates.</RV2R_Cheats_StopBleeding_Tip>
  <RV2R_Cheats_NoExtremeTemp>No extreme temps</RV2R_Cheats_NoExtremeTemp>
  <RV2R_Cheats_NoExtremeTemp_Tip>Caps a prey's hypothermia and heat stroke hediffs to 30%. Can potentaly be used to cheat out of cold snaps/heat waves.</RV2R_Cheats_NoExtremeTemp_Tip>
  <RV2R_Cheats_HyperHealing>Curaga Vore</RV2R_Cheats_HyperHealing>
  <RV2R_Cheats_HyperHealing_Tip>Healing preds start casting curaga instead of cure, tripling the strength of healing vore and dramaticaly improving the best vore goal.\n\nHaving a skilled doctor tend injuries and then heal-vore is still more effective, and prey don't get a resting bonus when fighting infection(even though they should).</RV2R_Cheats_HyperHealing_Tip>

</LanguageData>
